A Guide to the National Committee on United States-China Relations records, Audiovisual Materials, RG 10 FA1318
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Audio Recordings, 1967-2004; 1; All items are 1/4 inch audio tape unless otherwise noted.
  - United States - China Dialogues, 1991-2002; D
    - Ninth United States - China Dialogue, Pocantico Conference Center - Tape 9 of 9, 1997 December 12-15; 8 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Box 2, Tape AV 15512)
    - Eleventh United States - China Dialogue, Pocantico Conference Center - Tape 1 of 10, 2002 June 14-16; 61 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Box 2, Tape AV 15547)
    - Eleventh United States -China Dialogue, Pocantico Conference Center - Tape 2 of 10, 2002 June 14-16; 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Box 2, Tape AV 15548)
    - Eleventh United States - China Dialogue, Pocantico Conference Center - Tape 3 of 10, 2002 June 14-16; 25 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Box 2, Tape AV 15549)
    - Eleventh United States - China Dialogue, Pocantico Conference Center - Tape 4 of 10, 2002 June 14-16; 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Box 2, Tape AV 15550)
    - Eleventh United States - China Dialogue, Pocantico Conference Center - Tape 5 of 10, 2002 June 14-16; 17 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Box 2, Tape AV 15551)
    - Eleventh United States - China Dialogue, Pocantico Conference Center - Tape 6 of 10 (Blank Tape), 2002 June 14-16; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Box 2, Tape AV 15552)
    - Eleventh United States - China Dialogue, Pocantico Conference Center - Tape 7 of 10, 2002 June 14-16; 21 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Box 2, Tape AV 15553)
      Recording captures informal conversation and background noise.
    - Eleventh United States - China Dialogue, Pocantico Conference Center - Tape 8 of 10 (Blank Tape), 2002 June 14-16; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Box 2, Tape AV 15554)
    - Eleventh United States - China Dialogue, Pocantico Conference Center - Tape 9 of 10, 2002 June 14-16; 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Box 2, Tape AV 15555)
    - Eleventh United States - China Dialogue, Pocantico Conference Center - Tape 10 of 10, 2002 June 14-16; 72 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Box 2, Tape AV 15556)
    - Eleventh United States - China Dialogue, Pocantico Conference Center - Tape 11, 2002 June 14-16; 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Box 3, Tape AV 15557)
    - Eleventh United States - China Dialogue, Pocantico Conference Center - Tape 12, 2002 June 14-16; 47 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Box 3, Tape AV 15558)
    - Eleventh United States - China Dialogue, Pocantico Conference Center - Tape 13, 2002 June 14-16; 19 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Box 3, Tape AV 15559)
  - America - China Society, 1989-1994; E
- Video Recordings, 1971-2008; 2; 2 Cubic Feet 49 video recordings
  Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
  Audiovisual recordings of conferences, seminars, symposia, and NCUSCR programs, events, and exchanges. Some Chinese films and television broadcasts are also included. The series notably includes recordings of Ussuri Project meetings, 1993-1995; videos documenting teacher exchanges and instruction in U.S. and Chinese schools; the U.S. Foreign Policy Colloquium, 2003; and the U.S. visit of the Chinese Table Tennis delegation in 1972.
  - National Committee on U.S. - China Relations, Asia Society, Council on Foreign Relations, Secretary of State Warren Christopher Address, and Questions, 1996 May 17; Sound, Color, 53 minutes; VHS (Box 6, Tape AV 11894)
  - Shanghai Communique 25th Anniversary Delegation - Shanghai Program, 1997 March 2; Sound, Color, 7 minutes; VHS (Box 6, Tape AV 11895)
    OTV News broadcast on the commemoration and the Sino-U.S. Seminar held in Shanghai. Includes interviews with David M. Lampton, John Holdridge, Robert McNamara, and others.
  - Council on Foreign Relations and National Committee on U.S.-China Relations, China and the United States - Strategic Partners or Adversaries, Session One, 1997 June 2; Sound, Color, 80 minutes; VHS (Box 6, Tape AV 11896)
  - Council on Foreign Relations and National Committee on U.S.-China Relations, China and the United States - Strategic Partners or Adversaries, Session Two, 1997 June 2; Sound, Color, 87 minutes; VHS (Box 6, Tape AV 11897)
  - Trade Associations Workshop - Delegation Trip to Beijing, Chengdu, Xian, Shanghai, 1999 April 23 - May 3; Sound, Color, 71 minutes; VHS (Box 6, Tape AV 11898)
  - Chinese news program, circa 1990s; Sound, Color, 36 minutes; VHS (Box 6, Tape AV 11899)
    Program includes the segment "Guests in Dalian," on American teachers teaching English in Chinese Schools. Includes Karen Levin, at Dalian No. 1 Middle School.
  - Cherry Creek Schools, "A Year in Suzhou - China Teacher Exchange", 1998-1999; Sound, Color, 14 minutes; VHS (Box 6, Tape AV 11900)
    Exchange teacher at Souzhou Middle School, 1998-1999 school year.
  - Nova: Secrets of Lost Empires: "Rainbow Bridge" - Town of Jinze (Shanghai, PRC) (PBS-TV), 2000; Sound, Color, 57 minutes; VHS (Box 6, Tape AV 11901)
  - A Glimpse of China - Newton, MA - Beijing Jingshan Educational Exchange, 1997; Sound, Color, 35 minutes; VHS (Box 6, Tape AV 11902)
  - To Taste a Hundred Herbs: Gods, Ancestors and Medicine in a Chinese Village, 1986; Sound, Color, 60 minutes; VHS (Box 6, Tape AV 11903)
  - KidsFirst, North Woods Elementary School - China Segment, 2003 March; Sound, Color, 5 minutes; VHS (Box 6, Tape AV 11904)
    La Crosse, WI.
  - Performance, Product and Beyond: Arts Education in the School District of La Crosse, 1997; Sound, Color, 17 minutes; VHS (Box 6, Tape AV 11905)
  - La Crosse, Wisconsin Schools, 1996 October; Sound, Color, 20 minutes; VHS (Box 6, Tape AV 11906)
  - Experience China: Teaching and Learning, Sights and Sounds, 1997; Sound, Color, 35 minutes; VHS (Box 6, Tape AV 11907)
    Video by Karen Levin, concerning her experience and life in China as an exchange teacher at Dalian No. 1 Middle School. Two sections: Teaching and Learning (13 minutes) and Sights and Sounds (20 minutes).
  - China Symposium - Anchee Min, 2004 December 4; Sound, Color, 82 minutes; VHS (Box 6, Tape AV 11908)
    Anchee Min talk and performance. Symposium not identified.
  - Karaoke-style Chinese Songs, Sound, Color, 7 minutes; VHS (Box 6, Tape AV 11909)
    Title and lyrics written in Chinese characters and transliterated. Two New Year's songs: He Xin Nian and Gong Xi Gong Xi (Kung Shi Kung Shi).
  - Children's English Speech Contest, 1998; Sound, Color, 24 minutes; VHS (Box 6, Tape AV 11910)
    Held in Changzhou. Topic: Going out into the Wider World.
  - Bangor, Maine, News segment on Teaching Chinese Language at James F. Dougherty School, 2002-2003; Sound, Color, 3 minutes; VHS (Box 6, Tape AV 11911)
    Exchange teachers Gao Chengchun and Wang Xiuzhen.
  - Chinese language programs: Jackson Middle School, Portland, Oregon, and Milton Public Schools, Milton, Massachusetts, Sound, Color, 100 minutes; VHS (Box 6, Tape AV 11912)
    Chinese language class at unidentified school in Milton, MA (37 minutes). In the segment on Jackson Middle School in Portland, OR, students introduce themselves and film a video tour of their school, ostensibly addressed to their counterparts in China.
  - U.S. Foreign Policy Colloquium - National Committee on U.S.-China Relations: 1) Welcome, 2) Lecture - Chuck Hagel, 2003 June 5; Sound, Color, 104 minutes; DVCPRO (Box 6, Tape AV 11913)
    Colloquium at George Washington University: The Elliott School of International Affairs
  - U.S. Foreign Policy Colloquium - National Committee on U.S.-China Relations: 1) Leon Fuerth, 2) Karl F. Inderfurth, 2003 June 6; Sound, Color, 127 minutes; DVCPRO (Box 6, Tape AV 11914)
  - U.S. Foreign Policy Colloquium - National Committee on U.S.-China Relations: 1) Madeline K. Albright, 2003 June 6; Sound, Color, 57 minutes; DVCPRO (Box 6, Tape AV 11915)
  - U.S. Foreign Policy Colloquium - National Committee on U.S.-China Relations: 1) David Cohen, William Lane, Susan Molinari, 2003 June 6; Sound, Color, 84 minutes; DVCPRO (Box 6, Tape AV 11916)
  - U.S. Foreign Policy Colloquium - National Committee on U.S.-China Relations: 1) Discussion on Cuban Missile Crisis/Thirteen Days Discussion: Robert S. McNamara, 2003 June 6; Sound, Color, 55 minutes; DVCPRO (Box 6, Tape AV 11917)
  - U.S. Foreign Policy Colloquium - National Committee on U.S.-China Relations: 1) Dr. Richard Haass, 2) Media in US Foreign Policy, 2003 June 7; Sound, Color, 117 minutes; DVCPRO (Box 6, Tape AV 11918)
  - U.S. Foreign Policy Colloquium - National Committee on U.S.-China Relations: 1) Foreign Policy Roundup, 2003 June 7; Sound, Color, 110 minutes; DVCPRO (Box 6, Tape AV 11919)
  - U.S. Foreign Policy Colloquium - National Committee on U.S.-China Relations: 1) Group Exercises, Site Visits, 2003 June 7; Sound, Color, 78 minutes; DVCPRO (Box 6, Tape AV 11920)
  - U.S. Foreign Policy Colloquium - National Committee on U.S.-China Relations: 1) The US and China, 2) Closing Remarks: Dr. Harry Harding, John L. Holden, 2003 June 7; Sound, Color, 110 minutes; DVCPRO (Box 6, Tape AV 11921)
  - Greeting from Mrs. Barbara Bush, 1995; Sound, Color, 3 minutes; BetacamSP (Box 6, Tape AV 11922)
    Former United States First Lady Barbara Bush sends her videotaped greetings to the New York gala dinner for the National Committee on U.S.-China Relations.
  - China Town Hall: Local Connections, National Reflections, 2007 May 31; Sound, Color, 33 minutes; BetacamSP (Box 6, Tape AV 11923)
    From Washington, D.C., NCUSCR Director Steve Orlins in a conversation with Deputy Assistant Secretary of State Tom Christiansen.
  - China Town Hall: Local Connections, National Reflections, 2008 April 17; Sound, Color, 48 minutes; BetacamSP (Box 6, Tape AV 11924)
    NCUSCR Director Steve Orlins in a conversation with Norm Ornstein.
  - 11th Asian Games Opening Ceremony in Beijing - Part 1, 1990; Sound, Color, 124 minutes; VHS (Box 7, Tape AV 11933)
  - 11th Asian Games Opening Ceremony in Beijing - Part 2, 1990; Sound, Color, 120 minutes; VHS (Box 7, Tape AV 11934)
  - Red River Valley (English-subtitled), Sound, Color, 93 minutes; VHS (Box 7, Tape AV 11935)
  - Dru C. Gladney - CNN International Interview, "Global View" show with Ralph Beglieter, 1997 March 21-23; Sound, Color, 24 minutes; VHS (Box 7, Tape AV 11936)
    Interview on ethnic tensions in Xinjiang province.
  - "Common Ground" Promo - Welcome to television history - and the cutting edge of US-China communications, Sound, Color, 11 minutes; VHS (Box 7, Tape AV 11937)
    Promo for news program produced by Skyarc International Media.
  - Sino-American Relations: James R. Sasser, former US Ambassador to China, 2001 April 11; Sound, Color, 60 minutes; VHS (Box 7, Tape AV 11938)
    A CAN TV Community Partners production. Lecture series on Redefining the U.S.-China Relationship, cosponsored by the National Committee and the Chicago Council on Foreign Relations.
  - Ussuri Project - American Team Visit to Harbin, 1993 May 29; Sound, Color, 108 minutes; VHS (Box 7, Tape AV 11939)
    American team members included David M. Lampton, Douglas P. Murray, David Gordon, and George Davis.
    Tape was labeled simply "Douglas P. Murray" and dated 1993 May 29.
  - Soong Ching Ling Foundation's Projects in Ningxia, 1994; Sound, Color, 26 minutes; VHS (Box 7, Tape AV 11940)
    Local education and development projects, in cooperation with Plan International. Narration in English.
  - Scholar Orientation Program Reunion, Beijing, 1996 June 23; Sound, Color, 60 minutes; VHS (Box 7, Tape AV 11941)
    Reunion program and reception for SOP alumni in Beijing and Shanghai. A reunion in China was originally planned for late 1995, but it was postponed until June 1996.
  - Life in Tibet, early 1990s?; Sound, Color, 32 minutes; VHS (Box 7, Tape AV 11942)
    Life in Tibet, Past and Present. Film by the Central Newsreel and Documentary Film Studio of the People's Republic of China.
  - The Panchen Lama's Last Days, post - January 1989; Sound, Color, 21 minutes; VHS (Box 7, Tape AV 11943)
    Video in English, produced by the Central Newsreel and Documentary Film Studio of the PRC, about the 10th Panchen Lama.
  - Ussuri Project - Land Use Planning Delegation to the U.S., 1994 August; Sound, Color, 124 minutes; VHS (Box 7, Tape AV 11944)
    Joint delegation from China and Russia, 1994 July 30 - August 14. Meetings and discussion with U.S. delegates at Lake Placid, NY; visits.
    Video in Chinese and some English. Tape was labeled "Ussuri Team to the U.S., 1994, shot by Dang Dexian."
  - Ussuri Project - Steering Committee First Meeting, Harbin, 1995 February; Sound, Color, 65 minutes; VHS (Box 7, Tape AV 11945)
    Loud static/hiss in audio track makes sound unintelligible. At around 35 minutes, the video briefly plays at too fast a speed.
    Steering Committee First Meeting, Ussuri River Watershed Sustainable Land Use Joint Project among China, Russia, and the United States. Meeting in Harbin, China. U.S. delegation included David M. Lampton, Douglas Murray, and George Davis.
  - Chinese TV Program - Ping Pong exchange, 71 in China, 72 in US, 1971-1972; Sound, Color, 80 minutes; VHS (Box 7, Tape AV 11946)
  - Chinese Footage: Ping Pong - 71 China 72 US, 1971-1972; Sound, Color, 81 minutes; VHS (Box 7, Tape AV 11949)
  - Chinese Table Tennis Delegation in U.S.A., 1972 April; Sound, Color, 35 minutes; VHS (Box 7, Tape AV 11948)
    Chinese ping pong team U.S. visit (Detroit, Williamsburg, Washingtion, DC, New York, Memphis, Los Angeles, and San Francisco). In English. Film produced by the Central Newsreel and Documentary Film Studio of the PRC, September 1972.
  - ABC-TV Wide World of Sports: Ping Pong Exchange, 1972 April 15; Sound, Color, 89 minutes; VHS (Box 7, Tape AV 11950)
    Chinese table tennis team in Detroit. Footage of games and visits. The program recording includes commercials and other sports coverage.